[
 { 
    "question": "What is JavaScript?",
    "answer": "JavaScript is a client-side and server-side scripting language inserted into HTML pages and is understood by web browsers. JavaScript is also an Object-based Programming language"
},
{
    "question": "Enumerate the differences between Java and JavaScript?",
    "answer": "Java is a complete programming language. In contrast, JavaScript is a coded program that can be introduced to HTML pages. These two languages are not at all inter-dependent and are designed for different intent. Java is an object-oriented programming (OOPS) or structured programming languages like C++ or C, whereas JavaScript is a client-side scripting language."
},
{
    "question":"What are JavaScript Data Types?",
    "answer": "Number, String, Boolean, Object, Undefined"
},
{
    "question":"What is the use of is NaN function?",
    "answer": "isNan function returns true if the argument is not a number; otherwise, it is false."
},
{
    "question":"Which is faster between JavaScript and an ASP script?",
    "answer": "JavaScript is faster. JavaScript is a client-side language,, and thus it does not need the assistance of the webserver to execute. On the other hand, ASP is a server-side language and hence is always slower than JavaScript. Javascript now is also a server-side language (nodejs)."
},
{
    "question":"What is negative Infinity?",
    "answer": "Negative Infinity is a number in JavaScript which can be derived by dividing negative number by zero."
},
{
    "question":"Is it possible to break JavaScript Code into several lines?",
    "answer": "Breaking within a string statement can be done by using a backslash \"\" at the end of the first line."
},
{
    "question":"9. What are undeclared and undefined variables?",
    "answer": "Undeclared variables are those that do not exist in a program and are not declared. If the program tries to read the value of an undeclared variable, then a runtime error is encountered.\nUndefined variables are those that are declared in the program but have not been given any value. If the program tries to read the value of an undefined variable, an undefined value is returned."
},
{
    "question":"What are global variables? How are these variable declared?",
    "answer": ""
},
{
    "question":"Global variables are available throughout the length of the code so that it has no scope. The var keyword is used to declare a local variable or object. If the var keyword is omitted, a global variable is declared.",
    "answer": ""
},
{
    "question":"What is 'this' keyword in JavaScript?",
    "answer": "'This' keyword refers to the object from where it was called."
},
{
    "question":"What is the working of timers in JavaScript?",
    "answer": "Timers are used to execute a piece of code at a set time or repeat the code in a given interval. This is done by using the functions setTimeout, setInterval, and clearInterval.\nThe setTimeout(function, delay) function is used to start a timer that calls a particular function after the mentioned delay. The setInterval(function, delay) function repeatedly executes the given function in the mentioned delay and only halts when canceled. The clearInterval(id) function instructs the timer to stop.\nTimers are operated within a single thread, and thus events might queue up, waiting to be executed."
},
{
    "question":"What is the difference between ViewState and SessionState?",
    "answer":"\n'ViewState' is specific to a page in a session.\n'SessionState' is specific to user-specific data that can be accessed across all web application pages."
},
{
    "question":"Does JavaScript support automatic type conversion?",
    "answer": "Yes, JavaScript does support automatic type conversion. It is the common way of type conversion used by JavaScript developers"
},
{
    "question":"What are all the looping structures in JavaScript?",
    "answer":"Following are looping structures in Javascript:\nFor\nWhile\nDo-while loops"
},
{
    "question":"What is called Variable typing in Javascript?",
    "answer":"Variable typing is used to assign a number to a variable. The same variable can be assigned to a string. \nExample:\ni = 10;\ni = string;"
},
{
    "question":"How can you convert the string of any base to an integer in JavaScript?",
    "answer": "The parseInt() function is used to convert numbers between different bases. parseInt() takes the string to be converted as its first parameter. The second parameter is the base of the given string.To convert 4F (or base 16) to integer, the code used will be:parseInt ('4F', 16);"
},
{
    "question":"Difference between '==' and '==='?",
    "answer": "“==” checks only for equality in value, whereas “===” is a stricter equality test and returns false if either the value or the type of the two variables are different."
},
{
    "question":"What would be the result of 3+2+”7″?",
    "answer":"Since 3 and 2 are integers, they will be added numerically. And since 7 is a string, its concatenation will be done. So the result would be 57."
},
{
    "question":"How to detect the operating system on the client machine?",
    "answer":"In order to detect the operating system on the client machine, the navigator. Platform string (property) should be used."
},
{
    "question":"What do you mean by NULL in Javascript?",
    "answer":"The NULL value is used to represent no value or no object. It implies no object or null string, no valid boolean value, no number, and no array object."
},
{
    "question":"What is the function of the delete operator?",
    "answer":"The delete keyword is used to delete the property as well as its value.\nExample\nvar student= {age:20, batch:'ABC'};\nDelete student. age;"
},
{
    "question":"What is an undefined value in JavaScript?",
    "answer":"Undefined value means the\nVariable used in the code does not exist\nVariable is not assigned to any value\nProperty does not exist."
},
{
    "question":"What are all the types of Pop up boxes available in JavaScript?",
    "answer":"\nAlert\nConfirm and\nPrompt"
},
{
    "question":"What is the data type of variables in JavaScript?",
    "answer":"All variables in JavaScript are object data types."
},
{
    "question":"What are JavaScript Cookies?",
    "answer":"Cookies are the small test files stored in a computer, and they get created when the user visits the websites to store information that they need. Examples could be User Name details and shopping cart information from previous visits."
},
{
    "question":"What a pop()method in JavaScript is?",
    "answer":"The pop() method is similar to the shift() method, but the difference is that the Shift method works at the array's start. The pop() method takes the last element off of the given array and returns it. The array on which it is called is then altered.\nExample\nvar cloths = ['Shirt'\n'Pant', 'TShirt'];\ncloths.pop();\n//Now cloth becomes Shirt,Pant"
},
{
    "question":"Does JavaScript has concept level scope?",
    "answer":"No. JavaScript does not have concept-level scope. The variable declared inside the function has scope inside the function."
},
{
    "question":"What are the disadvantages of using innerHTML in JavaScript?",
    "answer":"If you use innerHTML in JavaScript, the disadvantage is\nContent is replaced everywhere\nWe cannot use it like “appending to innerHTML\nEven if you use +=like “innerHTML = innerHTML + 'html'” still the old content is replaced by html\nThe entire innerHTML content is re-parsed and builds into elements. Therefore, it's much slower\nThe innerHTML does not provide validation, and therefore we can potentially insert valid and broken HTML in the document and break it"
},
{
    "question":"What is break and continue statements?",
    "answer":"Break statement exits from the current loop. \nContinue statement continues with next statement of the loop."
},
{
    "question":"What are the two basic groups of data types in JavaScript?",
    "answer":"\nThey are as—Primitive\nReference types"
},
{
    "question":"How can generic objects be created?",
    "answer":"Generic objects can be created as:\nvar I = new object();"
},
{
    "question":"What is the use of a type of operator?",
    "answer":"'Typeof' is an operator used to return a string description of the type of a variable."
},
{
    "question":"Which keywords are used to handle exceptions?",
    "answer":"Try-Catch-finally is used to handle exceptions in the JavaScript"
},
{
    "question": "What is the use of the blur function?",
    "answer":"Blur function is used to remove the focus from the specified object."
},
{
    "question": "What are the different types of errors in JavaScript?",
    "answer": "There are three types of errors:\nLoad time errors: Errors that come up when loading a web page, like improper syntax errors, are known as Load time errors and generate the errors dynamically.\nRuntime errors: Errors that come due to misuse of the command inside the HTML language.\nLogical Errors: These are the errors that occur due to the bad logic performed on a function with a different operation."
}
]